Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Subscription: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
My Lady, you haven't eaten anything. Please eat something.
Your Highness, State Prince Dun's wife,
Lady Borjigin is here.
I have only met her once.
Why would she come to visit a sick
concubine who is out of favor?
Ask her to return to her affairs.
Yes.
I wasn't expecting Your Ladyship.
I came to pay my respects to the Empress Dowager,
and also Her Majesty the Empress.
Please sit.
I heard Your Highness is unwell
so I came for a visit.
I'm ashamed to be seen this way by Your Ladyship.
I shouldn't be having visitors while I'm ill.
I didn't expect that Your Ladyship would visit.
Please pardon my discourtesy.
I cannot believe that in just three or four months ...
Your Highness has ...
I appreciate Your Ladyship's concern.
I brought a box of ginseng with me today.
I hope Your Highness will accept it
and that it will help with your recovery.
I thank Your Ladyship.
Prince Dun is known to have a short temper.
If he has ever offended Your Highness,
or if Your Highness distrusts this gift,
I understand if Your Highness prefers to discard the ginseng.
Why would I?
Your Ladyship is overthinking.
I was not summoned for a visit
so I shouldn't stay longer.
I'll visit Your Highness again another day.
I hope Your Highness will soon recover your health.
Jin Xi, please see Her Ladyship out.
Yes.
My Lady.
My Lady, the ginseng ...
Should we dispose of it?
Although her husband is not friendly to us
the ginseng is a sign of her goodwill.
Send it to Dr. Wen.
Perhaps it can be used by the Imperial Infirmary.
Yes.
I've been ill for so long.
I never would have expected she would want to visit me.
People's hearts run hot and cold.
Fortunately, Lady Vertu and Consort Estime
also care about Your Highness very much.
You should let servants do this for me.
It's my pleasure doing this for Your Majesty.
I'm happy that this
can make Your Majesty more comfortable.
"Within his court, if a King does not have
law-abiding officials and worthy counselors,"
"and if abroad there are not hostile states
or other foreign aggression,"
"his kingdom will generally come to ruin."
"Hence, in calamity, one thrives;
in comfort and ease, one perishes.”
Mencius speaks the truth.
[respected disciple of Confucius]
Wealth and comfort corrode one’s resolve.
King Gou Jian “slept on brushwood
and tasted gall” to stoke his revenge.
“Think of danger in times of peace.”
“Shutter the windows before it rains.”
This was the way of the ancient rulers.
Do you agree?
I do.
Your Majesty has spoken so much...
Have some water to soothe your throat.
If Concubine Sourire were here,
she would converse at length with me.
Sourire is well-read and talented.
Her insights into history are always thoughtful.
I heard she fell ill with the advent of autumn.
Have you visited her? How is she?
Sourire's illness is in the heart, after all.
If Your Majesty visits her,
she will recover quickly.
It's not that I don't want to go ...
"The closer to home you get, the more insecure you become."
I dare not visit her.
How is her neck?
It got much better.
The scratches didn't leave any scars.
That's good.
A woman's appearance matters the most.
Your Majesty, I have a humble request.
Rise and speak.
Yes.
Since Sourire lost her child,
she has been living in unbearable grief
and that caused her illness.
If Your Majesty is not able to visit her,
it would be nice to let her family visit.
It would give her a chance to talk about her sadness
and let out her feelings.
The pain of losing her child ...
will be comforted by her family.
But she harbors resentment towards
Consort Nian and I.
If she talks to her family,
that would fuel her resentment rather than quelling it.
That would not be good for her recovery.
Your Majesty has considered every angle.
I did not think of that.
You are like a sister to her.
There's nothing wrong with advocating on her behalf.
Your Majesty was reading
“One errs, and then one corrects.”
I know that sentence.
I often make mistakes in front of Your Majesty
and I have strived to rectify them.
I hope that...
Your Majesty appreciates my effort.
You understand the sentence
but the smart Concubine Sourire does not.
It doesn't matter whether she understands it or not.
But she must remember one thing:
Your Majesty is the Emperor
and Your Majesty is always right.
Don't return to your palace tonight. Stay with me.
Your Majesty,
you must have forgotten Lord XVII is invited
to appreciate Dong Qichang's calligraphy books.
His Lordship has already arrived.
He's not a busy man.
He will stay at the Hall of Converging Light
and I will see him another day.
Is the dress you're wearing made of Shu Brocade?
Your Majesty surely remembers
that the Shu Brocade you awarded me
was sent to the Household Department
by you to make me a new dress.
The Shu Brocade ...
looks very good on you.
When the Household Department receives
more pieces, I'll give them all to you.
I thank Your Majesty
My Lady has been ill only a short time,
but it's become it's so deserted here,
"one could catch sparrows".
People reveal their true nature over time.
Now I realize,
those people who were once close
were taking advantage of My Lady's high favor.
His Majesty rarely comes to the harem these days
except for visiting the Empress and
the Palace of Prolonging Happiness.
I don't like to say "take advantage",
but we'll be at a dead-end if we have no value to anyone.
Your words are harsh,
but it’s the truth.
In the palace,
only those who are useful can survive.
We have to become useful,
and content with being used.
Then we can use others.
Discussing it won’t help us.
We must think of a solution.
Although Noble Lady An sees His Majesty most frequently now,
she is not a person we can count on.
Su Peisheng is just a servant, not able to weigh in.
It has to be someone whose words
carry weight and who we are able to meet
so they can talk some sense into My Lady.
I heard that Lord XVII is living in the Palace now.
How would that help?
His Lordship isn't someone we can meet.
You have been here for half a day.
Why have you been looking at me like this?
I’m just wondering
what it would look like
if you had truly lost faith in His Majesty.
Meizhuang, you think...
I have not lost faith in His Majesty?
What do you think?
If you had actually lost faith in His Majesty,
you would have already recovered from your illness.
Instead of sitting here,
you could visit His Majesty even if he does not come,
so this palace wouldn’t be lifeless like the Cold Palace.
His Majesty will come if he is willing.
If he’s not,
I can't force that to happen.
You are not like I am.
His Majesty has much deeper affection for you.
He confined me, and didn't want
to hear or ask about me.
That helped me to understand
he is fickle and unreliable.
Now he treats me as if I was invisible,
but I don’t really mind it.
But you are different.
Because I have more affection than you do
for His Majesty?
If you had no affection for him,
you would be just like me.
Not a thing he does or says would sadden you.
In fact...
You already understand.
His Majesty has not lost his affection for you.
But still, Lingrong was close to us.
Even though her words mismatched her deeds,
do I really have to compete with her for His Majesty's favor?
And now, His Majesty favors Lingrong more than me.
You helped her gain favor when you were in favor,
but has she ever helped you when she's in favor?
If she helps you, you won't need to compete for favor.
If she doesn’t,
do you plan to stay out of favor
until the end of your days?
And, His Majesty,
he will have a favored concubine one day
and a different favored the next.
It will always change.
We women in the palace are just fighting for slightly more favor than the others.
If your heart has truly died for His Majesty,
you wouldn't be wasting your time on grief.
Meizhuang...
I’m so stupid, aren’t I?
In this palace,
I had hoped for a shred of love and tenderness.
I should have expected that least of all.
Huan’er...
There are already too many broken hearts in the palace.
Don't be another one of them.
I understand.
All right.
I must pay respects to the Empress Dowager.
I’ll see you tomorrow.
Do you often visit Her Majesty recently?
Since my recovery, I don't feel for His Majesty as before.
Now that Lingrong is exclusively in favor,
and His Majesty barely comes to the harem,
I sought a way to ensure my status.
Her Majesty must be very fond of you.
Her Majesty is unwell.
Spending my time with her is better than
being an idle person in the palace.
I will go now.
You have worked hard, Madam.
Allow me to do this for you.
Whenever you're here, you make their work much easier.
You do so many tasks and errands for them.
I rarely have the chance to spend time with Your Majesty.
Please allow me to fulfill my filial duty.
Rarely?
You come here every single day.
If Your Majesty is troubled by my coarseness,
I won’t dare to come again.
You’re mild-natured and careful.
I enjoy your company.
I'm honored that Your Majesty says so.
Careful, it was quite hot.
I appreciate your time,
but I have to remind you.
You should spend more time with the Emperor if possible.
Lady Fuca and Concubine Souire have lost their children.
The Emperor is in grief and he needs someone to be there for him.
I believe “who tied the bell should be the one to untie it”.
His Majesty is sad because of Concubine Souire’s loss.
It would be good if she could spend more time with His Majesty.
If that is a knot in the heart that cannot be untied,
it would make things even worse if they are together.
Things will not work out
until one of the two thinks through it
and makes the first move.
Yes.
My Lady, the moon is clear and bright tonight,
Shall I get Endless Longing, your zither?
It is an elegant pastime to play the zither to the moon.
However, as Li Bai wrote,
"Endless longing, shatters my heart in ruins."
I’d rather not play it.
The poem Endless Longing used to be your favorite, My Lady.
Even if I like the poem,
I dare not to play it anymore.
You're not playing it on the zither,
but someone is playing it on the flute.
This is the second half of the Endless Longing.
"Endless longing, for the person in Chang'an."
"Her beauty is the blossom behind the clouds."
"Above me, the ink-blue layers of skies;"
"Beneath, the clear waves of Lushui River.”
"My soul is tortured traversing the heavens and the land"
"yet my dreams cannot cross the barricading mountains.”
Jade, listen...
What beautiful flute playing!
My Lady, what are you talking about?
I don't hear anything.
Don't you?
No, I don't.
The flute playing is light and graceful.
I didn't know another musician in the palace
admires Endless Longing as much as you, My Lady.
Endless Longing is a sorrowful song.
This flute playing
heightens the sense of longing
but lessens the lament.
It makes longing appear to be a beautiful feeling.
I wonder which concubine is playing the flute so well.
You also feel touched by the playing, don't you?
My Lady, why don't we go out to seek the player?
The ancient poets followed a fragrance to seek the blooming plums,
now I follow the sound of the flute to find the player.
The sound is as light as a wisp of cloud.
I wonder if I am able to find the player.
I am also curious to meet the player.
The encounter would be most fortunate.
But if we don't, that's fate.
You've lost weight.
Just as in the season when "the west wind reels the bamboo curtain",
I have become "thinner than the wilting lilies."
[a poem by Li Qingzhao]
Your Lordship saved me in a time of distress.
I will always remember and appreciate Your Lordship's righteous act.
Concubine Sourire, you don't have to be so formal with me.
I am sorry—
sorry that it did not save your child.
Everyone thinks that Your Lordship entered
the Palace of Earthly Honors
only because I am a concubine in His Majesty's favor
and that Your Lordship saved me to please His Majesty.
But regardless,
in this entire palace,
only Your Lordship extended a hand of justice.
I'm not in a position to repay Your Lordship
but I'm not a person who would ungratefully forget your kindness.
Should anything inconvenience Your Lordship in the future,
I will aid with all I have.
I care about your well-being
because ...
you are someone who understands me.
I know Your Lordship did so for my benefit,
but if Your Lordship stays in close contact with my maid,
it would be of no benefit to Your Lordship's reputation.
Thank you, Concubine Sourire.
Why is Your Lordship here tonight?
His Majesty asked me to stay for the night.
When I went to pay my respects to him,
A Nobel Lady surnamed An was singing inside.
I believe I had met her before.
She was then Attendant An.
Was she?
Her singing has progressed a lot,
but... it no longer reflects her own character.
That the Emperor likes it is most important,
isn't it?
Raw jade and unpolished gold
are beautiful in their natural texture.
It's more important to be loyal to oneself.
“Love perishes; One who loves many will love none.
Heart persists; One who indulges their heart will not lose it.”
I hope my playing of Endless Longing relieved some of your sorrow.
It's just a poem.
Poetry speaks to the heart
—not only yours, but also mine.
His Majesty probably asked Your Lordship
to stay so he can meet you tomorrow.
I should take my leave.
When did you become close with Lord XVII?
I'm talking to you as your elder sister.
You don't need to answer if you aren't willing to.
Huan, I had no intention to conceal.
Was it on my birthday?
You were preventing me from taking a walk near the lake.
It was at his bidding, wasn't it?
And you entreated him to enter the Palace of Earthly Honor?
Jinxi had to stay with you in the Palace of Earthly Honor
and the Empress Dowager was acutely unwell.
No one else in the palace could stand up for you.
So I made the bold decision to seek His Lordship's help.
How many times have you met each other?
Only twice.
The first time was after you had the miscarriage
and the other was this afternoon.
His Lordship only told me to take care of you, Huan.
Why is it ... Huan ... that you would ask so?
Did His Lordship tell you about this?
You made an informal bow to His Lordship tonight.
Had you not met him privately before,
you would have bowed to him formally.
This was my negligence
I'm in an awkward situation.
If you two are in close contact,
that will not benefit us or His Lordship.
Stop meeting him in private.
Spring, you've arrived.
Congratulations, My Lady, on your
delightful service to His Majesty last night.
I must deliver Her Majesty's bidding.
As usual,
here is the medicine.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Now we have to do the needlework ourselves.
I'm to blame for this.
Not at all.
The servants in the palace are snobbish as always.
This time,
the Household Department is busy sewing
Shu Brocade dresses for Lady An.
(laughs inwardly)
Actually, I prefer making new clothes for myself.
They are more comfortable and warm to the heart.
Lingrong is a blessed concubine.
It is her time to be so exclusively favored.
Meizhuang.
Why are you making winter clothes yourselves?
The Household Department is too busy to look after my palace.
Since it's getting colder,
we have to make the clothes ourselves.
Come. I have something to show you.
Can I go after I sort out the yarn?
No.
Where are we going?
You'll find out.
Meizhuang, it's the Cold Palace ahead of us.
Don't slow down.
(When will His Majesty come?)
(I won!)
(You cheated. I won't play with you anymore.)
(His Majesty will favor me one day.)
(Does His Majesty even remember you?)
(You smell of mildew!)
(Give it to me!)
(I won't!)
Guess who she is.
Are you all right?
I hope you didn't take me here
just to see Concubine Beauté.
Did you notice the woman lying next to her?
She was a Noble Lady.
Who is she?
Who she is matters not.
What matters is that she was pregnant
but had an accidental miscarriage.
She drowned herself in sorrow and
fell out of His Majesty's favor.
Later, when she claimed that
Consort Fleur was the murderer of her child,
she was banished to the Cold Palace.
Are you afraid...
that I will follow in her footsteps?
No one knew whether or not
her accusation was slander.
But His Majesty believed it was.
“Absence makes a man forgetful.”
She buried herself in grief
and neglected His Majesty.
So she did not even have a chance
to explain to His Majesty in person.
She is guilty even if she's not.
This is the lesson:
If you indulge your depression,
what they are now,
will be your end in the future.
The Shu Brocade His Majesty awards you is really nice.
You will look charmingly elegant wearing it.
His Majesty will grow even fonder of you.
I am too humble to wear Shu Brocade.
All that is precious and rare
should belong to Your Majesty.
Therefore, I present all the Shu Brocade to Your Majesty.
His Majesty favors you.
He already granted you the gold-woven robe.
In comparison to His Majesty's favor,
these Shu Brocades are insignificant.
This wouldn't be possible without Your Majesty's grace.
I will never forget Your Majesty's mercy.
Rise.
You are very thoughtful.
That's why His Majesty awarded you many more
pieces than what Concubine Sourire received before.
How do you feel being exclusively favored?
I understand that
I could never achieve this without Your Majesty's guidance.
All right, I know you do.
You wanted to replace Concubine Sourire in the palace.
And your wish has been realized.
Consort Nian is domineering
and Concubine Sourire too sharp.
I don't like them.
You seem to be more sensible, so I fulfilled your wish.
That is also fulfilling to me.
But you have to keep one thing in mind ...
I took the medicine every time after serving His Majesty.
I'm glad you did.
It's not that I'm not allowing you to have a child.
It's because you've been newly favored
and other concubines would steal your position
taking advantage of your pregnancy.
You are still young and have ample years ahead of you.
I appreciate Your Majesty's advice.
Come quickly.
Concubine Sourire ...
Why were you walking so carelessly?
It’s only been a few months that you haven't seen His Majesty.
Have you forgotten the rules in the palace already?
It is my fault to have accidentally bumped Your Highness.
I was wondering who would dare to offend Consort Austuce.
But I'm not surprised to see Concubine Sourire,
who used to be His Majesty's favorite.
The most favored concubine never looks anyone in the eye.
I hope Your Highness will pardon me—
Oh!
You've now remembered to apologize to Her Highness?
Forget it, let's go. Seeing her is not good luck.
Your Highness, of course it is not.
But, she caused you and the Third Prince to be separated.
It was my inadvertent mistake.
I ask for Your Highness's forgiveness—
Concubine Sourire has always been most
respectful of her superiors and the palace rules.
But...
Why is it that you are just talking,
instead of kneeling to Her Highness?
I ask for Your Highness's forgiveness.
All right.
I would appreciate it as long as you stay out of my sight.
Stay out of my way.
Your Highness, she offended you.
You can't let her go unpunished.
Forget it.
I don't have the time to waste my breath standing in the wind.
I will just let her go.
If I may remind Your Highness...
Now that Consort Nian is out of favor,
Consort Estime is undistinguished,
and Consort Honnête is ailing,
you are the only admired Consort in the palace.
If you don't assert your authority now,
who will acknowledge your rank in the future?
If Your Highness recalls -
His Majesty neglected our palace
because of this bewitching Concubine Sourire,
her child overcame mine like "Fire overcomes Wood",
and the Third Prince cannot visit you!
I haven't forgotten!
It was you.
It was all your fault!
Lady Fuca, you said my child overcame yours.
But what about my child?
Who overcame my child?
As I lost my child, you received yours.
As I was devastated, you were enjoying
the height of His Majesty's favor.
Who else should be responsible for my loss?
As for the loss of your child,
that's the fate you deserve!
Lady Fuca, if you insist so,
there's nothing I can say.
Haven't you said enough?
If you had not reported to the Empress,
why would Her Majesty punish Consort Astuce?
That was all your fault, wretch!
Every action has a consequence.
Your Highness understands the reason
why Her Majesty imposed the punishment.
I decided to let it go
so I did not report it to His Majesty.
Otherwise,
the punishment on Your Highness
would not just be separation from the Third Prince.
Very well.
Well said!
You dare to openly offend me.
Huh?
Apple...
Slap her until she bleeds.
I beg Your Highness's pardon.
Apple, there's nothing you should worry about.
Now that His Majesty doesn't see her anymore,
it is Consort Astuce's rightful authority
to discipline a Concubine.
She defamed her superior.
She deserves it!
Apple, if you delay by one more moment,
I will send you to the Department of Penalty.
Do it!
Keep going!
Now you have learned.
You know that talking doesn't help
and that you should endure it.
I believe Consort Nian certainly
taught you a valuable lesson.
Stop.
You have the time to be slapped
but I don't have the patience to watch.
You will kneel in the cold wind
and reflect on your offense.
Apple, stay with her.
Until she has knelt for two hours.
Now that Concubine Sourire is not pregnant,
I believe two hours will be fine.
Only the pain on her body
will make her realize the pain in our hearts.
Your Highness Consort Astuce,
do you have to do this?
You would very much like to run
and tell to Her Majesty, wouldn't you?
But now you have no evidence.
What if I did put oleander into the cakes?
Do you still have them?
If you dare to speak of it again,
I will punish your crime of slandering.
Concubine Sourire must not be mad.
I believe Your Highness would rather endure two hours of kneeling.
Do you think you are still where you were?
It's time to go.
The Household Department is expecting
us to select the tributary offerings.
Would Your Highness rather stand?
I won't tell anyone.
Apple, is it the Palace of Earthly Honor ahead?
Yes.
How is Consort Nian?
Consort Nian is well in the Palace of Earthly Honor.
She is ...
Everything is all well.
Peace to Your Majesty.
Peace to Lady An.
Your Majesty, Jiang Fuhai saw Consort Astuce
punishing Concubine Sourire on Long Street.
She is being slapped.
Is His Majesty informed?
His Majesty is at court.
Whatever happens in the harem
should not spread to the court.
Why should I care about her
when His Majesty doesn't?
Your Majesty, Concubine Sourire was already unwell.
Can we ...
ask Consort Astuce to stop?
You pity Concubine Sourire.
But who will pity you?
If I pity her, His Majesty will, too.
I’m afraid your favor will vanish if that happens.
Yes.
Hurry! Don’t look!
Your Highness, it's been two hours.
Please stand up.
I'm sorry Your Highness had to suffer this.
Consort Astuce isn't normally like that.
You will be rewarded for your kindness.
Let me support Your Highness on your way back.
No need.
My Lady, rolling a boiled egg on your cheeks
will help reduce the swelling.
She has gone too far in this.
I will report to the Empress.
I was on my knees for so long.
How could she not know?
She would have come if she wanted to.
My Lady, why did you submit to Consort Astuce?
It wouldn't matter if you confronted her.
Confront her?
Who am I to confront her?
Lady Fuca was right.
The pain on the body
made me realize the pain in the heart.
Vermilion.
Ask Xiao-Yunzi to capture some butterflies.
My Lady,
it's hard to find butterflies this time of the year.
Butterflies are out of season.
But I must acquire some.
And they must be the most beautiful kind.
Yes.
Jade, bring some rouge and powder here.
The rouge and powder have run out.
Go to the Household Department and get some.
The Persian Ink has also run out, hasn't it?
Yes.
Forget it.
Now I don’t deserve painting my eyebrows using Persian Ink.
Just bring the ink pens you paint your eyebrows with.
I'll do it right away.
Xiao-Yunzi, there is a butterfly!
Where?
There it is!
It's dead.
Even if it was alive,
such an ugly butterfly, what use would it be?
I can't even do what My Lady asked me to.
I'm useless.
Where can we find butterflies this time of the year?
I know a place.
Where is that?
Changping Palace has hot springs.
It’s warmer and there will still be flowers there.
I believe there will also be butterflies.
But we can’t get out of the palace.
Besides, no one plans to go to Changping at the moment.
Keep looking around.
Keep looking, everyone! I'll be back shortly.
Jade, you always come in so quietly and startle us.
Your Lordship, if Ajin keeps saying that,
I will not dare to visit you anymore.
Stop it.
Does the Palace of Pearl Jade have a request for me?
Please, Jade.
You’d better not say it.
Last time, you came tearfully
to ask His Lordship to console Concubine Sourire.
I wonder what task it is this time.
That's enough.
Please don't hesitate to ask.
Your Lordship, I don’t understand why,
but My Lady asked us to capture butterflies.
How is that possible this time of the year?
I’m afraid Your Lordship didn’t do well comforting her
and she became confused in her sadness.
Other than butterflies, what does she want?
Nothing else.
If butterflies can help her overcome her grief,
I will do my best to find them.
Other than that, you should spend more time with her.
It’s almost winter now.
Where can we find butterflies?
I heard there are hot springs at the Changping Palace.
Maybe there are butterflies there.
Then I will go to Changping,
It’s not very difficult.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Subscription: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.